<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="person">
    <email>archenroot@gmail.com</email>
    <name>Ladislav Jech</name>
  </maintainer>
  <longdescription>
    VMware Tools is a suite of utilities that enhances the performance of the
    virtual machine's guest operating system and improves management of the
    virtual machine. Without VMware Tools installed in your guest operating
    system, guest performance lacks important functionality. Installing VMware
    Tools eliminates or improves these issues:
    - Low video resolution
    - Inadequate color depth
    - Incorrect display of network speed
    - Restricted movement of the mouse
    - Inability to copy and paste and drag-and-drop files
    - Missing sound
    - Provides the ability to take quiesced snapshots of the guest OS
    - Synchronizes the time in the guest operating system with the time on
      the host
    - Provides support for guest-bound calls created with the VMware VIX API
    
    VMware Tools includes these components:
    - VMware Tools service
    - VMware device drivers
    - VMware user process
    - VMware Tools control panel
    
    VMware Tools is provided in these formats:
    
    ISOs (contain .tar files): These are packaged with the product and are
    installed in a number of ways, depending upon the VMware product and
    the guest operating system installed in the virtual machine. For more
    information, see the Installing VMware Tools section. VMware Tools provides
    a different ISO file for each type of supported guest operating system:
    - Windows
    - Linux
    - NetWare
    - Solaris
    - FreeBSD.
    
    Operating System Specific Packages (OSPs): These are downloaded and
    installed from the command line on an ESXi/ESX host. VMware Tools is
    available as separate downloadable, light-weight packages that are specific
    to each supported Linux operating system and VMware product. OSPs are
    an alternative to the existing mechanism for installing VMware Tools and
    only support Linux systems running on ESXi/ESX. To download OSPs and
    to find important information and instructions, go to
    http://www.vmware.com/download/packages.html.
    
    For a list of supported guest operating systems, go to
    http://www.vmware.com/resources/compatibility/search.php?deviceCategory=software.
    
    Binary releases available at:
    http://softwareupdate.vmware.com/cds/vmw-desktop/player/
  </longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
